# 怪味面
Strange flavor noodle.
# 想什么味 有什么味
It has all the flavor you can possibly think of.
# 这就是怪味的特点
This is the uniqueness of this flavor.
# 麻酱
Sesame sauce.
# 先加酱油
We add soy sauce first,
# 酱油最好用生抽是吧 生抽就行
Light soy sauce is recommended.
# 有的颜色喜欢重一点
However, if you prefer darker color,
# 可以略微的加一点老抽
you can add a little bit dark soy sauce.
# 加酱油要少慢慢加
We will add soy sauce gradually,
# 要不然油一分离芝麻酱就不润了
otherwise it will separate from the sesame sauce.
# 一点一点加
Gradually.
# 这个和好以后能保存 搁在冰箱里头
Once we are done making the sesame dressing, it can be stored in the fridge
# 十天半个月没问题
up to 15 days.
# 但要切忌的就是葱姜蒜现吃现拌
However, we won't add spring onion, ginger, and garlic into it until we need to eat the sauce.
# 把葱姜蒜放到里头
If you put them along with the sesame sauce into the fridge.
# 搁半个月就不行了
It won't last as long.
# 变味了就 有点臭葱烂蒜味
It will stink.
# 这酱油差不多了
This much soy sauce should be enough.
# 搁点醋（米醋） 醋根据自己的喜好
Add some rice vinegar
# 可多可少
base on your preference.
# 我们这个怪味就是
This so called "strange flavor"
# 你想有什么味就有什么味
has all the flavor you can possibly think of.
# 说有酸味 那就是里边有醋
You can taste sourness, because we have added vinegar into it.
# 你看这稀稠 差不多了
This stickiness is good.
# 好了 放盐
Okay, let's add salt.
# 盐也别太多
Not not too much.
# 大约十克
Around 10g.
# 少来一点味精
A little bit of food MSG.
# 这花椒也要根据自己的喜好
Add Sichuan peppercorn also base on your own preference.
# 有的说我是爱吃麻的 就多放点
If you love numb flavor, add more.
# 花椒味可出来了 这是昨天现焙的
Those peppercorns smell so good. They are freshly roasted yesterday.
# 略微要放点糖
We need to add a little bit sugar.
# 我们要放点香油 香油不少
Sesame oil is a key ingredient.
# 吃面得有油 没油它香不了
Delicious noodle needs oil.
# 这都好了吧 这还准备芝麻
Is everything prepared? We still need sesame seeds.
# 这芝麻买的是熟芝麻
This is cooked sesame seeds.
# 这也别太多 太多了也油大
But don't add too much, it will be too oily.
# 今天调这些正好是
Those are
# 我中午和大妈的午饭
me and my wife's lunch.
# 今天调的没调那么多
Not too much food honestly.
# 第二个环节 切点小料
Now, we will prepare some other ingredient.
# 切点小葱花
Slice some spring onions.
# 这个怪味是多种味道的合成
This "strange flavor" combines many others flavors.
# 有的人说我爱吃小米辣
If you like Xiaomila chili pepper,
# 我不爱搁辣椒油
but you don't like red chili oil,
# 这里边搁点小米辣 葱花
you can add some Xiaomila and chopped spring onions.
# 姜 爱吃姜的可以多搁点
If you love ginger, you can add more ginger.
# 不爱吃的少搁 再不吃就可以不搁
If you don't like ginger, you can add less or even none.
# 不搁就没这味了
There's going to be no flavor if you don't add ginger.
# 这个汁兑好以后有多用
This dressing is versatile.
# 怪味凉面 怪味粉皮 怪味鸡丝
You can make noodle, rice noodle, or shredded chicken with it.
# 那个也挺好吃 白斩鸡
Baizhan Chicken (cold boiled chicken) is also a good accompany with this dressing.
# 煮好了 买两大鸡腿一煮
Boil the chicken drumsticks,
# 煮完了切成条
slice them.
# 怎么让你一说 立马就来食欲
I am getting hungry.
# 关键是味儿 姜米
The key is the flavor, minced ginger,
# 蒜末
minced garlic,
# 黄瓜 面条的黄瓜要切细
and cucumber, finely sliced cucumber.
# 炒菜的黄瓜要切粗一点
You will need to slice it thicker if you are instead making a fried dish.
# 黄瓜丝切好了
We have finely sliced the cucumber.
# 咱把这汁再调调啊
Let's further season the dressing.
# 这怪味儿什么叫标准
What is a good "strange flavor"?
# 我给大家简单的说说
I will tell you briefly.
# 闻 一闻着就香
It should smell fragrant,
# 然后味觉
And,
# 我想葱姜味 有
it has the flavor of spring onion, ginger
# 酱油味 有
soy sauce,
# 咸鲜味 有
salt and fresh.
# 一尝 后面还有点胡椒
After you take a sip, it has some peppercorn aftertaste,
# 到嗓子上还有点微辣
spiciness,
# 然后到嗓子眼儿还有点小酸
and even some sourness.
# 这就是怪味的特点
This is the uniqueness of this "strange flavor".
# 想什么味 有什么味
It has all the flavor you can possibly think of.
# 吃面条就得硬面
The dough has to be hard.
# 有的面可能筋度不够
Otherwise it won't be as chewy.
# 稍微往里边可以放点盐
We can add a little bit salt.
# 用凉水和 和的硬一点 然后手擀
Use cold water to harden it, and hand roll it.
# 面擀好了 大爷给切一下
The dough is done, let Da Ye slice it.
# 我擀的 大妈擀的
This is my noodle; this is my wife's.
# 瞧这认真劲儿的 一气呵成
So clean.
# 左撇子还挺溜
Left-handed Da Ye is quite skillful.
# 抖了抖了
I choked, whoops.
# 这叫一板儿面
This is a board of noodle.
# 水开了 下锅了
Water is boiling. We can add the noodles in.
# 你看大爷家常备的 还备了辣椒油
See, Da Ye always has red chili oil in his house.
# 辣椒油也跟网友说一下
As for this chili oil,
# 先用点香油把这辣椒面给它和一下
we need to mix sesame oil with paprika first.
# 咱们家都吃的差不多了
We are almost running out of chili oil.
# 剩一碗底了 就你们吃的
You guys ate all of it.
# 完了以后把油烧热
After mixing paprika and sesame oil.
# 面好了 搁点什么油 花生油
Noodles are done. Add some peanut oil into the pan.
# 我们要再搁点香油 把油烧热
Along with some sesame oil, and heat them up.
# 烧热以后往那辣椒面里一呲
Then pour all the oil into the mixed paprika.
# 呲第一勺的时候 你要看这油的温度
You have to watch the temperature the first time you add oil.
# 如果这油温过热 呲第二勺的时候
If it is too hot,
# 等这油温晾一晾 再呲
wait until the oil cools and add further.
# 要不然它就糊了
Otherwise, it will burn.
# 这是最简单的呲红油的方法
This is the easiest way to make chili oil.
# 一勺一勺的搁
Add the hot oil gradually.
# 不要一下子都搁进去 那就糊了
It will burn if you dump all of them in once.
# 这个味儿还真是挺冲的
This flavor is quite strong.
# 经过腌制以后 蒜香葱香非常香
After marinating, the garlic and spring onion flavor is really fragrant.
# 咱们今天就按份儿走 黄瓜丝
This is today's ration. Add the cucumber slices.
# 这是大爷的 一会再给大妈盛一碗
This is Da Ye's. I will give my wife her ration.
# 为什么不先给我盛
Why don't you give me first.
# 不是 这展示啊 要搁点辣椒啊
No, this is to show the audience. I will add some paprika on top.
# 把汁儿往上一浇
Pour the dressing in.
# 来点辣椒油
Some chili red oil.
# 有的喜欢吃热乎点的
If you like hot food,
# 可以把辣椒面搁这上头
you can put some paprika on top.
# 拿热油呲
and pour in some hot oil.
# 大妈给照一相 咱们上菜了
Let's take a picture.
# 家有大厨 就是幸福
Good chef, good life.